About

I'm professionally experienced with Full-Stack Web Development and DevOps and I have been building websites since 2015. Software development is my passion and for the past two years I have been exploring the world of software, specifically framework, network, web, app, and game development in Unity and C#. Check out my online portfolio at https://iothebanner.dev!

Work Experience

MindFire Technology - Software Consulting - Layton, Utah

Jr. Developer - October - 2019 - April 2020

Worked with a team in several tech stacks on many different projects, with a focus on fullstack development. The tech stacks I primarily worked with included .Net Core, VueJS, Vuex, ReactJS, Redux, and RavenDB.

Echo Broadband - Internet Service Provider - North Salt Lake City, Utah

Jr. DevOps - March 2019 - August 2019

Developed FETCH (see projects) and worked on the company website. Quickly and thoroughly solved network errors. Worked with customers to resolve local network issues.

Varex Imaging Corporation - X-Ray Tube Manufacturing - Salt Lake City, Utah

Production Operator - 2018 - March 2019

Manufactured X-Ray tubes. Managed time as a team to meet production deadlines. Thoroughly documented and updated manufacturing processes.

H&R Block - Tax Preparation - *Utah*

Tier1 & Tier 2 Tech Support - 2016 - 2018

Provided technical support and customer service to tax professionals. Maintained and fixed infrastructure, software, and networks for tax offices. Worked with developers to improve and debug the tax preparation software.

Education

Davis Applied Technology College - Kaysville, Utah

Software Engineering, GPA: 3.94

Member of the National Technical Honor Society

Learned about computer hardware, networking, web development basics, cyber-security, object-oriented languages such as Java and C#, databases, algorithms and data structures. Worked on several projects such as Project Librarian (see project section) and the Canvas API application.

Technical Skills and Certifications

General Use - C#, Java, JS(ES6+)

Backend - NodeJs, ExpressJS, .Net Core, PHP

Frontend - HTML5, CSS3, JS, React, Vue

Databases - SQL, NoSQL

Operating Systems - Linux, Windows

Version Control - Git

Game Development - Unity

MTA Network Fundamentals

CompTIA Strata IT Fundamentals

Davis Technical College - Software Development

Some Significant Projects

GameWorkJS

- An extensible, modular approach to JS based game/visual experience development. Currently HTML Canvas elements are supported by the Camera and renderable-component modules.
- Utilizing Git, JS, and NodeJS.

MysticNetworking

- A complete TCP/UDP networking solution built in C#, consisting of modular software suites which manage server-client interactions and provide structure for creating verifiable low-level packets.
- Utilizing Git, C# with an emphasis on the .Net Sockets module, Unity for prototyping the UX.

GopValues

- A reddit clone with a focus on political discussions.
- Utilized Git, Postman, NodeJS, NoSQL RavenDB, ASP.NET Core API, and Vue with Vuex.

FETCH - Data Collection and Monitoring

- A data collection and monitoring system for the data distribution infrastructure of a mid-sized ISP.
- Utilized **Git**, **Docker**, **Ubuntu Server**, Telegraf, Clickhouse, and Grafana.

Retinal Roaster

- A device capable of locating and guiding a laser to human eyes in camera view.
- Raspberry Pi as the main processor. Servomotors for horizontal and vertical interactors. PiCamera to capture video input.
- Utilized Python and OpenCV.

Project Librarian

- Developed a web application which tracks the borrowing of DavisTech classroom books.
- Built with Linux on a Raspberry Pi.
- Utilized **PHP**, HTML 5, CSS 3, **JS**, and **MySQL**.

Canvas API Application

- Developed an app which assists instructors in student and material management for Canvas by Instructure.
- Utilized C# and Instructure's RESTful APIs.